const e=JSON.parse(`[{"number":1,"question":"Which of the following statements regarding Naltrexone is true?","options":{"A":"Naltrexone is a strong antagonist at S-and K-opioid receptors","B":"Naltrexone's antagonistic effect on //-type opioid receptors is responsible for causing nausea","C":"Naltrexone has >90% oral bioavailability","D":"Naltrexone undergoes extensive first-pass metabolism","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Naltrexone is a strong antagonist at S-and /r-type opioid receptors. Its antagonistic effect on //-type opioid receptors is responsible for causing nausea. Naltrexone is rapidly well absorbed with approximately 96% of the dose absorbed from the GI tract; however, it is subject to significant first-pass metabolism."},{"number":2,"question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding Varenicline?","options":{"A":"Varenicline's antagonistic activity at a subtype of the nicotinic receptor is responsible for its mechanism of action","B":"It is efficacious in relapse prevention","C":"Food has no effect on its bioavailability","D":"Patients quit successfully with bupropion than with Varenicline","E":"Diarrhea is the most common side effect"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Varenicline is a partial agonist—antagonist at α4β2 subtype of the nicotinic acetylcholine receptors. Varenicline works by blocking nicotine from attaching to the receptors and decreases the release of dopamine. Food has no effect on its bioavailability."},{"number":3,"question":"Buprenorphine's advantages over clonidine, in the management of patients with opioid withdrawal, include better control of which of the following symptoms?","options":{"A":"Nausea","B":"Cramping","C":"Craving","D":"Diarrhea","E":"Sweating"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Although clonidine reduces many of the autonomic effects of opioid withdrawal syndrome, nausea is better controlled with buprenorphine."},{"number":4,"question":"All of the following are true regarding buprenorphine induction EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"It is recommended that patients present in mild, observable, spontaneous opioid withdrawal on the day of buprenorphine induction","B":"Patients are expected to spend at least 2 hours in the office during the induction day","C":"The maximum buprenorphine dose recommended for the first day is 6mg","D":"Because buprenorphine is a partial opioid agonist, it is possible that the drug may precipitate opioid withdrawal","E":"For induction, only the sublingual buprenorphine formulation and not the transdermal formulation should be used"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"The recommended maximum dose of buprenorphine on the first day is 12 to 16mg. Subsequently, the buprenorphine dose can be titrated and maximum daily dose is about 24mg per day."},{"number":5,"question":"Which of the following statements regarding buprenorphine is true?","options":{"A":"Buprenorphine is given sublingually and not orally to minimize abuse","B":"Buprenorphine prolongs the QTc interval at therapeutic doses","C":"Buprenorphine has a slow rate of dissociation from opioid receptors","D":"Buprenorphine is a partial agonist at the μ-opioid receptors and an antagonist at κ-opioid receptors","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Buprenorphine has a slow rate of dissociation from opioid receptors, and when terminated after chronic therapy, no withdrawal syndrome is observed."},{"number":6,"question":"All of the following statements regarding naltrexone are true EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"It is a competitive antagonist at the opioid receptor","B":"The drug acts by reducing the rewarding effects of alcohol through blocking the release of dopamine","C":"Concurrent use of tramadol, a centrally acting opioid analgesic, with naltrexone can precipitate acute opiate withdrawal reaction","D":"A long-acting injectable preparation of naltrexone is available","E":"It is Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved for opiate and alcohol dependence"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"There is no drug-drug interaction between naltrexone and tramadol. Hence, tramadol can be safely used for analgesia in patients on naltrexone therapy."},{"number":7,"question":"What is the minimum washout period for patients taking methadone before the first dose of an opioid receptor antagonist such as Naloxone or Naltrexone?","options":{"A":"5 days","B":"2 weeks","C":"10 days","D":"3 weeks","E":"4 weeks"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Patients receiving naltrexone for narcotic addiction should be detoxified before naltrexone administration because naltrexone will reverse the effects of narcotic analgesics in dependent persons, resulting in withdrawal symptoms."},{"number":8,"question":"A 27-year-old white man was diagnosed with brief psychotic disorder. After 6 months, he started drinking alcohol heavily and was given a diagnosis of alcohol dependence. His family threatened to disown him, following which he agreed for an admission to a chemical dependency unit. He actively participated in group therapy and individual therapy but refused medications. With persuasion, he was commenced on disulfiram as an aversive conditioning treatment for alcohol dependence. Soon after his discharge, he started acting strangely; he believes that the FDA is after him and refuses to leave his house for fear of being monitored by aliens. Physical examination is unremarkable. Drug testing is negative, and he denies relapse. What is the most likely diagnosis?","options":{"A":"Substance-induced mood disorder","B":"Disulfiram-induced exacerbation of psychosis","C":"Schizophrenia","D":"Schizophreniform disorder","E":"Delirium tremens"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Disulfiram is associated with wide ranges of psychiatric effects such as depression, agitation, paranoia, and bizarre behaviors. The emergence of psychotic symptoms with the patient's treatment with Disulfiram suggests that Disulfiram contributed to the occurrence of his symptoms."},{"number":9,"question":"All of the following medications are FDA approved for the treatment of smoking cessation pharmacotherapy EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Varenicline","B":"Bupropion","C":"Nicotine","D":"Clonidine","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Varenicline, nicotine replacement therapy, and bupropion are FDA-approved treatments for nicotine dependence."},{"number":10,"question":"All of the following statements regarding methadone are true EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"FDA indicated for the management of opioid abuse and moderate to severe pain","B":"Contraindicated in patients with acute bronchial asthma","C":"Major route of methadone metabolism is through Cytochrome P450 3A4 (CYP 3A4)","D":"Starting doses of methadone can be as high as 80 to 100 mg per day","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"The maximum daily dose of methadone can be as high as 80 to 100 mg per day, not the starting dose."},{"number":11,"question":"In addition to its role in alcohol dependence, Disulfiram is clinically useful in which of the following substance dependence disorders?","options":{"A":"Methamphetamine dependence","B":"Marijuana dependence","C":"Cocaine dependence","D":"Nicotine dependence","E":"Inhalant dependence in adolescents"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"There is no FDA-approved treatment for cocaine dependence. There are some data from studies supporting the clinical use of Disulfiram for the treatment of cocaine dependence."},{"number":12,"question":"All of the following opioid antagonists are indicated in the management of opioid overdose EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Naloxone","B":"Naltrexone","C":"Nalmefene","D":"Nalbuphine","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Nalbuphine is an opioid analgesic with K-agonist/partial μ-antagonistic properties. It does not have a role in the management of opioid overdose."},{"number":13,"question":"Which of the following agents has no role in the management of alcohol withdrawal syndrome?","options":{"A":"Carbamazepine","B":"Chlordiazepoxide","C":"Lorazepam","D":"Diazepam","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Carbamazepine, chlordiazepoxide, lorazepam, and diazepam can be used to treat alcohol withdrawal syndrome."},{"number":14,"question":"All of the following are therapeutic uses of clonidine EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Opioid withdrawal","B":"Nicotine withdrawal","C":"Stimulant withdrawal","D":"Alcohol withdrawal","E":"Benzodiazepine withdrawal"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Clonidine has a role in the treatment of withdrawal from opioids, alcohol, nicotine, and benzodiazepines. It does not have a role in the treatment of stimulant withdrawal."},{"number":15,"question":"All of the following are differences between illicit GHB and sodium oxybate EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Illicit GHB is taken at frequent intervals, whereas sodium oxybate is taken at bedtime","B":"Illicit GHB is often taken with other illicit drugs, whereas sodium oxybate is not to be taken with alcohol or central nervous system (CNS) depressants","C":"Illicit GHB is more widely available than sodium oxybate","D":"GHB for nonmedical use is a schedule III drug, and when prescribed for medical indications, it is a schedule I substance","E":"None of the above"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Illicit GHB is taken at frequent intervals along with other drugs, whereas sodium oxybate is taken at bedtime and not to be taken with alcohol or CNS depressants. Illicit GHB for nonmedical use is a schedule I drug, and when prescribed for medical indications, it is a schedule III substance."},{"number":16,"question":"A 21-year-old male college student was brought in to the emergency department by his roommate for agitation and bizarre behavior for the past 2 hours. His roommate reports that the patient returned from a party and used a white crystalline powder. During examination, the patient appears confused and cannot engage in a conversation. He smells of alcohol, and his physical examination is remarkable for tachycardia, nystagmus, and miosis. Besides routine investigations and supportive care, which of the following might have a role in elimination of the drug from the patient's body?","options":{"A":"Alkalization of urine","B":"Acidification of urine","C":"Administration of phenobarbital","D":"Administration of lidocaine","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"The patient is intoxicated with hallucinogen phencyclidine (PCP). PCP levels are enhanced in acidic urine. Thus, acidification of urine is an adjunct therapy in PCP overdose."},{"number":17,"question":"A 43-year-old Caucasian man with alcohol-induced cirrhosis of liver was admitted for upper gastrointestinal (GI) bleed. His variceal bleeding was treated during this admission. He is medically stable and ready for discharge. He is requesting medications to help him prevent relapsing on alcohol. Which of the following would be your best choice?","options":{"A":"Naltrexone","B":"Lorazepam","C":"Disulfiram","D":"Acamprosate","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Acamprosate and naltrexone are FDA indicated in maintenance of abstinence in alcoholism. However, Acamprosate would be a better choice because it is safe to be used in patients with hepatic dysfunction."},{"number":18,"question":"Which of the following antidepressants can be considered as a second-line therapy for smoking cessation?","options":{"A":"Nortriptyline","B":"Mirtazapine","C":"Venlafaxine","D":"Duloxetine","E":"Fluoxetine"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"Nortriptyline and clonidine are commonly used as second-line agents and are not approved by FDA for the treatment of nicotine dependence."},{"number":19,"question":"Which of the following nicotine replacement formulations produces the most rapid rise in nicotine levels?","options":{"A":"Nicotine vapor inhalers","B":"Nicotine nasal spray","C":"Nicotine lozenges","D":"Nicotine gum","E":"Nicotine transdermal patch"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Among the different nicotine replacement therapy, nicotine nasal spray has the most rapid onset of action (peak action within 1 to 4 minutes), thus providing more immediate relief from cravings."},{"number":20,"question":"All of the following statements regarding methadone are true EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Concurrent use of methadone and Ziprasidone can increase QTc interval","B":"Mean plasma half-life of methadone is about 24 hours","C":"Methadone induces its own metabolism and can increase its clearance","D":"Methadone has very low risk for abuse","E":"Methadone is an agonist at the μ-opiate receptor"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Although methadone does not provide a quick or potent high, the availability of methadone for treatment and pain has increased its abuse potential."},{"number":21,"question":"The unpleasant Disulfiram-alcohol reaction is caused by accumulation of which of the following?","options":{"A":"Acetyl coenzyme A","B":"Acetaldehyde","C":"Aldehyde dehydrogenase","D":"Pyruvate","E":"Malondialdehyde"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Disulfiram irreversibly inhibits the enzyme acetaldehyde dehydrogenase that results in the accumulation of acetaldehyde."},{"number":22,"question":"All of the following statements about Acamprosate are true EXCEPT:","options":{"A":"Acamprosate attenuates hyperglutamatergic states that occur during early abstinence","B":"Acamprosate should be initiated in patients who are abstinent at treatment","C":"Like naltrexone, Acamprosate has shown to specially reduce heavy drinking","D":"The FDA-recommended dose of Acamprosate is 660 mg twice a day","E":"It is contraindicated in severe renal impairment"},"correct_answer":"C","explanation":"Acamprosate has been shown to reduce the frequency of drinking, not specifically heavy drinking as naltrexone has."},{"number":23,"question":"Naltrexone should not be prescribed concurrently with which of the following?","options":{"A":"Tramadol","B":"Oxycodone","C":"Diazepam","D":"Fluoxetine","E":"Diclofenac sodium"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Concurrent administration of naltrexone and opioid analgesics such as oxycodone is contraindicated because naltrexone will reverse the effects of narcotic analgesics resulting in acute withdrawal symptoms."},{"number":24,"question":"The efficacy of bupropion in tobacco cessation is because of which of the following?","options":{"A":"Antagonizing nicotinic acetylcholine receptors","B":"Dopamine reuptake inhibition","C":"Noradrenaline reuptake inhibitor","D":"Attenuate nicotine withdrawal symptoms","E":"All of the above"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Bupropion is FDA approved for nicotine dependence. It acts by antagonizing nicotinic acetylcholine receptors and inhibiting dopamine and noradrenaline reuptake."},{"number":25,"question":"A 36-year-old African American man is admitted to the intensive care unit for management of alcohol intoxication. His past medical history includes gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD), cirrhosis of liver, and hypertension. There is documentation of delirium tremens in his chart. His initial blood alcohol level is 35-0. A repeat blood alcohol level in 6 hours comes back as 75. Which of the following would be the most appropriate drug in his management?","options":{"A":"Chlordiazepoxide","B":"Lorazepam","C":"Diazepam","D":"Carbamazepine","E":"Clonidine"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Benzodiazepines such as diazepam, chlordiazepoxide, and lorazepam are used to prevent delirium tremens. However, diazepam and chlordiazepoxide are not indicated in a patient with liver cirrhosis."},{"number":26,"question":"Which of the following agents is the treatment of choice for opiate overdose?","options":{"A":"Buprenorphine","B":"Methadone","C":"Flumazenil","D":"Naloxone","E":"Phentolamine"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Naloxone, an opioid antagonist, is approved for the management of opioid overdose."},{"number":27,"question":"A 37-year-old African American man was admitted to the hospital for his elective septoplasty. He has alcohol dependence and is currently taking naltrexone. You are consulted regarding his pain management and clearance for surgery. What is your next best step?","options":{"A":"Initiate hydrocodone therapy","B":"Immediate surgery with diclofenac sodium for pain control","C":"Emergency surgery with hydrocodone for pain control","D":"Stop naltrexone and plan for surgery within 24 hours","E":"Stop naltrexone and plan for surgery in 72 hours"},"correct_answer":"E","explanation":"Naltrexone should be discontinued 48 to 72 hours before an elective surgery, where opioid analgesia may be required."},{"number":28,"question":"A patient with alcohol dependence and generalized anxiety disorder is requesting a medication for use on an as-needed basis for his anxiety attacks. Which of the following medications would be the most appropriate choice?","options":{"A":"Paroxetine","B":"Hydroxyzine","C":"Buspirone","D":"Lorazepam","E":"Chlordiazepoxide"},"correct_answer":"B","explanation":"Benzodiazepines should be avoided in a patient with active alcohol use. Hydroxyzine is FDA approved for the treatment of anxiety disorder and may be used on an as-needed basis."},{"number":29,"question":"Disulfiram should not be prescribed concurrently with which of the following?","options":{"A":"Fluoxetine","B":"Tramadol","C":"Naltrexone","D":"Metronidazole","E":"Lorazepam"},"correct_answer":"D","explanation":"Concurrent use of Disulfiram and metronidazole is contraindicated. When administered together they may result in CNS toxicity."},{"number":30,"question":"Which of the following must be closely monitored during Naltrexone therapy?","options":{"A":"Liver function test (LFT)","B":"Renal function test","C":"Thyroid profile","D":"Lipid panel","E":"Platelet count"},"correct_answer":"A","explanation":"LFTs should be closely monitored during naltrexone therapy. Initial screening at baseline and follow-up LFTs should be obtained after 1 month of Naltrexone treatment."}]`);export{e as default};
